Craig Neeson

Senior Frontend Engineer

craigneeson@hotmail.co.uk 07517099522

Website: https://craigneeson.co.uk/
Github: https://github.com/cneeson
Linkedin: https://tinyurl.com/2sn5z78a

About

Experienced front-end developer with a demonstrated history of contributing to projects used by a global user-base Specialising in React, Vue and TypeScript, enjoys working with diverse teams to create the best products for users to enjoy and the cleanest code for developers to maintain.

Frontend

Working on UI code is my passion in software development. I have extensive experience architecting and implementing UIs for the web and mobile using a variety development setups. I have a deep knowledge of JavaScript/Typescript and am just as comfortable working in vanilla JS as with a UI framework. I have architected web projects from the ground up and enjoy working with teams to strategise around solutions to some of the more challenging parts of UI design. I have experience working both as an individual contributor who owns the full frontend, and also as one of many team-players who all have a stake in the codebase.

Backend

I also have experience contributing to monolithic and micro/service-orientated projects in C#, Java and PHP (Laravel). As much as having accurate and up-to-date data contracts are important to me, I find it useful to have a surface-level understanding of the code behind APIs.

Personal

In a career that is largely focused on screens, I enjoy unwinding in the evening by listening to music and (attempting) to play a bit of guitar. I also try to get into the outdoors as much as possible by running and exercising. I an a techy at heart though, and will often have a few unfinished side-projects to tinker with too.

Technologies

A quick round-up of technologies that I have worked with over the years:

Highly Proficient

- Languages Typescript & Javascript
- Frontend frameworks Vue, Nuxt, React, React-Native
- Backend frameworks Node, Laravel
- **Styling -** CSS, SCSS,styled-components, tailwind
- Data management Redux, VueX, Pinia and react-query
- Testing frameworks Jest, Vitest, Cypress, Playwright
- Build tools webpack, rollup, vite, gulp
- CI tools Github Actions, Azure Pipelines, Heroku, Jenkins
- Monitoring Sentry, Grafana
- Analytics Segment, Hotjar, Heap, Google Analytics, Fullstory
- CMS Prismic, Sanity

Working Knowledge

- Visualisation ThreeJS, GSAP, AnimeJS
- Languages PHP, Java, C#
- Frontend frameworks Angular
- Build tools docker & kubernetes
- Infra AWS Lambda, SQS, SNS, Cloudfront, S3

Education



Ulster University

Bachelor of Science (BSc), Computing, First Class Honours.

January 2013 - Jan 2017 (4 years)

Experience



- Joined Ankorstore during a period of rapid growth, scaling from 50 to 400 employees in one year. Attracted
 to their mission to support brick-and-mortar shops against large online competitors.
- Worked with Vue and Nuxt to develop features for marketplace, order-fulfillment, and backoffice platforms, focusing on shipping and logistics.
- Key projects included developing tools to track shipments, visualize stock movements and visualise prospective shops in an **interactive map view**.
- Participated in **company-wide projects** such as re-brandings, Vue to Nuxt migrations, sale and event-related implementations, and new business model changes.
- Collaborated closely with product and data engineers to deliver analytics tracking for all features, allowing a data-driven approach to product development.



Locate a LocumSoftware Developer

Oct 2019 - Oct 2021 (2 years)

- Led the **modernization of UI** for this healthcare start-up's web and mobile apps, setting **ambitious technical goals** that transformed development practices.
- Set front-end standards and upskilled the team to accelerate delivery and reduce tech debt.
- Drove architecture changes to shift the LAL platform from a legacy stack to a server-rendered React stack.
- Built LAL's first fully documented React component library with a new UX designer, refreshing the brand.
- Created maintainable patterns for API data retrieval and caching, reducing boilerplate and improving state separation.
- Abstracted repeated data-fetching logic into shared NPM packages for React and React Native apps.
- Introduced TypeScript to UI repos, boosting code robustness; 40% of the codebase is now in TS.
- Delivered new modules for leave management, scheduling, clock-in, and payroll across web and mobile.

Flexera



UI Engineer & Associate UI Engineer

Sep 2018 - Nov 2019 (1 year, 2 months)

- Worked as part of a global team to build UIs for 8 different products, used by many of the world's Fortune 50 companies.
- Worked in close collaboration with UX designers to create Flexera's first component library with the aim of bringing visual consistency and behaviour to many newly acquired products.
- Standardised design token usage and UI behaviours via a component library, balancing design consistency and flexibility for future use cases.
- Worked with various acquisition teams, gaining exposure to different UI development approaches and technology stacks.
- Worked across many interesting and technically challenging products including a portal to visualise one of the world's largest technology asset datasets, a dashboard to visualise and optimise Azure, AWS & GCP cloud resource costs, and a network-security monitoring system.



- Worked in a small consultancy team to deliver full-stack solutions for many businesses in Northern Ireland.
- Delivered end-to-end sales, billing and production management systems for two large concrete factories.
 The systems integrated directly with production-line firmware and tracked vehicles in real-time, allowing coordinators to have a birds eye view of their operations.
- Developed internal processes, introducing Cl pipelines, private package registries, and a modular front-end component system using vanilla JavaScript and Handlebars.



Liberty Information Technology Associate Software EngineerJun 2017 - Dec 2017 (6 months)

- Worked on an integrations team to build the highly scalable infrastructure behind a greenfield insurance product.
- Gained exposure to many different languages (Kotlin, TypeScript & Scala) and AWS resources (Lambda, SQS & SNS) due to the sprawling micro-service architecture.
- Had my first experience of Agile at scale, LIT had adopted the SAFe Agile methodology.



Nitec Solutions Associate Software Engineer

Jun 2015 - Oct 2016 (1 year, 4 months)

- Gained exposure to older stacks (classic ASP, Microsoft Silverlight) as well as newer ones (.NET MVC apps, SPAs) due to the varying range of client projects and setups.
- Developed an agent program and UI to monitor backup status of client servers and desktops. Later, built
 the first version of a customer portal for real-time backup visualization, which remains in daily use by many
 of Nitec's customers.
- Helped to build a custom document management solution for an occupational therapy clinic in Belfast.
- Helped to build a **production management system** for Northern Irelands largest plastics manufacturer.

